Jamie Albertelli

jamiealbertelli.com

📞 (+44) 7547 247 392 | 💌 me@jamiealbertelli.com | 🖸 jamiealbertelli | 🛅 jamiealbertelli

PROFILE

Software Engineer with a combined 1 year of experience as a Front-End Developer in a professional R&D environment and as part of a Freelance team. Looking for a permanent role as a Junior in a Software Engineering team. Targeting both roles in London as well as UK based remote work.

EDUCATION

University of Essex Oct. 2018 - Oct. 2019

MSc Computational Finance

University of Sussex Sep. 2014 - Jul. 2018

BSc Computing for Digital Media

EXPERIENCE

Astriosoft May 2021 - Present Nicosia, Cyprus

Co-Founder / Software Engineer (astriosoft.com)

Focused on business solutions, producing Web Applications including a Logistic Tracking System.

- Held consultations with clients to discuss optimal platform strategy. Carried out the full Software Development Life
- Main Technologies: HTML, CSS, Laravel/Eloquent/PHP, Javascript, MySQL, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS.

Near East University - Robotics Lab

Sep. 2020 - May. 2021

Software Engineer

Nicosia, Cyprus

- Worked as part of a team to develop a Front-End for a Mechanical Ventilator Machine.
- Consumed RESTful APIs for user input and data visualisation.
- Main Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap 4.0, JQuery.

Immersive Learning Research Network (IRLN)

May 2020 - Jul. 2020 (Contract)

Publications Team - Editor

Remote

- Took responsibility for the structure, legality, and acceptability of 30 papers submitted for presentation at the ILRN 2020 conference.
- Worked in collaboration with other members of the IRLN editorial team. Reporting to the conference coordinator.

PROJECTS

FinTwit - Financial Correlation with NLP (Github Repo)

- Application built to seek whether or not tweets are indicative of stock price movements.
- Scraped Tweets and determined the general sentiment per historical range. Correlated mood with shares price movements to see if a relation exists between the two.
- Main Technologies: Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, Yahoo Finance Data.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript/Typescript Java, Python, SQL

Frameworks: TailwindCSS, Boostrap (With exposure to Laravel and ReactJS).

Tools: Git, Linux/UNIX, Jira, LaTeX, Adobe Suite